## Matt Bordas

Computational Biologist bordasmatt@gmail.com • (714) 342-2575 • LinkedIn • matthewbordas.com

#### **PROFILE**

Currently working as a computational biologist focused on using my experience as a software engineer to analyze, model, and understand omics data. I have a bachelor's in computer science and four years of industry experience in full stack software engineering at a startup I co-founded. I've worked with various of technologies, obtaining proficiencies in Python, Pandas, Jupyter Notebooks, Flask, ReactJS, NodeJS, DevOps, data analysis, cloud computing, and cloud architecture. I'm seeking a role in bioinformatics that will further progress my skills and broaden my exposure to the field. I'm moving to Washington DC and prefer positions within its proximity, but I am open to nearby east coast jobs (such as Cambridge) where I could work remote or split my time between being in person and working remote.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Amaral Lab, Northwestern University**

**Evanston, IL (remote)** 

# Visiting Scholar, Computational Biology

Sept 2020 - Present

Python, Pandas, Flask, Jupyter Notebooks, ReactJS, Docker, AWS

- Conducts research projects at the <a href="Amaral Lab">Amaral Lab</a> that fuse software, biology, and data science to understand and solve problems around aging
- Compiles and analyzes aging-related gene data from the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI) to develop interactive web applications
- Applies machine learning methods from research paper (Nat Genet 47, 856–860 (2015)) to construct a predictive model that would preemptively score the effectiveness, worthiness, and potential impact of new aging research

#### **Time by Ping**

San Francisco, CA

Co-Founder, Lead Engineer

May 2016 - Mar 2020

NodeJS, Docker, DevOps, AWS, MySQL, MongoDB, .NET, C#, Agile, TDD

- Led the engineering team through the company's first three fundraising rounds totaling over \$16 million
- Co-founded <u>Time by Ping</u> and developed the first version of an automated timekeeping product for lawyers and law firms
- Managed all engineering personnel and expanded the team from two to twelve people

#### Lead Full Stack Engineer

June 2019 - Mar 2020

- Facilitated the project management, automation, and development of a detailed technical pipeline for onboarding new customers to the platform
- Spearheaded the creation of a new engineering team focused on DevOps, SRE, new customer onboarding, and onsite support
- Worked with the CEO and leadership to restructure the engineering team post-series A fundraising

## **Head of Engineering**

Jan 2018 - June 2019

- Directed the engineering team to a successful series A fundraising round
- · Oversaw the development, testing, and release of the product to the company's first users
- Provided on-call and on-site support for all users across the U.S. and U.K.

#### **Software Engineer**

May 2016 - Jan 2018

- Hired interns and developed a prototype that secured the first customer contract
- Built and programmed the entire product from the ground up in coordination with the engineering co-founder
- Co-founded the company and collaborated with the founding team to outline the product requirements

## COMMUNITY

Code2040

San Francisco, CA

2019 - Present

Mentor/Coach

- Serves as a volunteer for <a href="Code2040">Code2040</a>, a non-profit focused on improving the lack of representation of women and people of color in the technology industry
- Supervises mentors and provides recommendations on how to best support and provide resources for their mentees
- Coordinates recurring check-ins and organizes group wide events

## **EDUCATION**

**University of California, Davis** 

Davis, CA 2012 - 2016